YETUNDE SOLA-ADEBAYO

ysolaadebayo@gmail.com https://github.com/Yetunde79/ www.yetundesolaadebayo.com

SUMMARY

Passionate Web Developer with 3+ years' experience in programming, seeking to leverage solid skills in math, logic, and cross-platform coding as a programmer for your company. Increased web traffic by 40% over 3 months. Creative self-starter who takes initiative with minimal supervision.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug. 2018

Minor in Mathematics University of Houston

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

September 2018-Present

Self employed

- Consulting with clients to outline website goals, illustrate wireframes and developing the website.
- Developing and deploying responsive websites using the most efficient web technology.
- Identifying and fixing bugs on the website, increasing web traffic by 10%.

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

May 2018-August 2018

Shoot Technologies

- Increased web traffic by 40% by creating websites, improving navigation, adding SEO and adding necessary plugins.
- Ensured the creation of a user-friendly interface by collaborating in preproject analysis and technical assessment by working with the web designer.
- Improved UX by using data from Hotjar and Google analytics.
- Analyzed user needs and software requirement to determine feasibility of design.
- Composed technical documentation to describe program development and requirement.

DESK ASSISTANT

October 2015-August 2018

University of Houston

- Improved accuracy and efficiency by maintaining detailed administrative and procedural processes.
- Trained new employees on how to efficiently do their jobs.
- Maintained and updated mailing and database systems using various computer software.
- Provided information concerning service in a manner that increased sales.

PROJECT ENGINEERING INTERN

June 2015-July 2015

Chevron Corporation

- Collaborated with engineers while being a resourceful team player to develop project plans for two major oil and gas projects.
- Developed the technical documentation for two major oil and gas projects

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

MongoDB

PHP

ES6

Framework

JQuery

Node.js

React.js

Bootstrap

Tools

Git

Agile(Scrum)

Visual Studio Code

Non-Technical

Leadership

Creativity

Critical thinking

Fast learning

Communication

Collaboration

OTHER PROJECTS

Weather Checker Website Contact Manager Scorecard Website

VOLUNTEERING

Code Park Teaching
Assistant
Houston Food Park Volunteer
Generation One Volunteer

PROJECTS

FOOD BLOG

Created a food blog using Node.js, Express.js, EJS, MongoDB/Mongoose and passport.js for login authentication.

MOVIE SEARCH WEBSITE

Developed a website that searches for movies and redirects to information on the movie using Node.js, Express.js, EJS, CSS and the OMDb API.

BIRTHDAY CHECKER

Developed an application using Java GUI with my group that checks the day of the week you were born and your zodiac sign.